# **Gary Shores**

## Full Stack Developer(.Net, C#, Python)

#### **Profile**

Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for web projects for 6+ years. Consistently identifying and providing the technological needs of companies through ingenious innovation. Proficient in developing databases, creating user interfaces, writing and testing codes, troubleshooting simple/complex issues, and implementing new features based on user feedback. Experienced participating in all aspects of the software development lifecycle, which includes estimating, technical design, implementation documentation, testing, deployment, and support of applications developed for various clients. Good Experience in Reactjs for creating interactive Uls using One-way data flow, Virtual DOM, JSX, and React Native concepts. Proven Front-End experience in developing UI's using HTMLS, C383, SASS, LESS, AJAX, JSON, JSP, JSF, jQuery, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, XML, Angular, and Node. JS.

## **Professional Experience**

### Full Stack Developer, OmniMD ☑

11/2020 - 01/2023

Hawthorne, CA, United States

- Assisted in product development and enhancements of current suite to boost engagement by 15%.
- Optimized the codebase by converting class components to functional components using React Hooks and some Redux stores to React context, resulting in the size of the codebase being reduced by 90%.
- Generated weekly progress updates and presented insights to the design team and project manager; improved project alignment and increased on-time delivery rate of significant projects by 15%.
- Integrated an automated property valuation model fed by machine learning Python data.
- Worked closely with an agile team of 10 members and provided end-to-end solutions for clients.
- Worked with UX/UI design teams to improve existing applications and increase conversion rates by 20%.
- Used DevOps, agile principles, and jenkins to enable CI/CD.
- Created five real-world eCommerce websites for various clients. One said, "You've increased my revenue by 50% overnight."
- Worked with Angular Forms, Validations, Modules, Components, directives, controllers, and HTTP Requests.
- Implemented RxJS for better user experience by dynamically providing Asynchronous request and response communication between the client and the server.

#### **Backend Developer,** *Qbatch* □

08/2017 - 10/2019

Sheridan, Wyoming, United States

- Creating and testing web apps concerning rental housing and craft services (C#, ASP, Java, ¡Query).
- Developed a node.js server to validate membership and track digital badges being used, saving the company \$22.5K.
- Learned and worked with 5 other platforms and technologies, including AP! Management platform, ESB, and AWS tools.
- Followed ARIA and Ally accessibility standards to ensure users with disabilities had highest quality UI/UX.
- Developed JUnit test suites to achieve 92% code coverage and allow the delivery of bug-free software.
- Designed a scalable backend system using Spring Boot, enabling the app to handle a 103% increase in concurrent user requests.
- Implemented Jenkins for continuous integration, which reduced manual effort by 53% and enabled faster release cycles.

#### **Frontend Developer Intern,** *Design Mate Pro* □

12/2015 - 08/2017 | Clifton, United States

- Implemented professional customer service, managing 20+ phone and email requests a day.
- Developed innovative techniques to allow clients to use headless CMS's with technology like Contentful and Google sheets to manage all marketing material.

- Used Angular controllers to control page data and Models to bind data in User Interface with controller.
- Developed code to call the web service/APIs to fetch the data and populate on the Ul using RxJS and Observables
- Implement RxJS for better user experience by dynamically providing Asynchronous request and response
- Used can-Deactivate, can-Activate to display the warning or information message when user is moving away or coming to particular routes.
- Streamlined project process for the design team and project manager; reduced project turnaround time by 10% through implementation of Agile methodology and JIRA project management software.
- Managed component state by using Redux, React-Redux, Redux-thunk, and hooks.

## **Education**

**Bachelor of Computer Science (BComSc),** *University of North Texas* 

04/2012 – 03/2016 | Texas, United States